<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>mikkeli.hacklab.fi</title>
   
   <link>http://mikkeli.hacklab.fi</link>
   <description>Avoin ja yhteisöllinen työtila tieteestä, teknologiasta ja digitaalisesta taiteesta kiinnostuneille Mikkelissä &bull; An open and community-based workspace for people with interest in science, technology and digital arts in Mikkeli</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> Hacklab Mikkeli</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Blender Course Report</title>
	  <link>//blender-course-report</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-02-20T12:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//blender-course-report</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>First course to begin our year 2016 was 3D modelling basics with <a href="http://www.blender.org/">Blender</a>. We asked what courses our community was interested in and 3D modelling basics was voted to first place. Luckily we have some talented Blender users in our members who also volunteered to lead the course. </p>

<p><img src="/public/images/blender-course.jpg" alt="Photo: People at Blender course"> </p>

<p>Earlier our courses have been about eletronics and robotics, so now we needed a whole different layout of tables and seating. Course material and instructing was also designed to suit the skills of participating people which varied from beginner to advanced. These facts made the course a test in many ways.</p>

<p>Everything went fine. Even better than expected. Many of participants found 3D modelling interesting and want to learn more. Easily worth the early wakeup on Saturday morning.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Hacklab Mikkeli 1 Year!</title>
	  <link>//hacklab-mikkeli-1-year</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-02-19T22:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//hacklab-mikkeli-1-year</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>We have survived as a registered association for one whole year! One year ago we met and decided to make this thing official - 19 brave hackers signed our charter of foundation. Of course we had began planning the hacklab earlier but after receiving huge support from other Finnish hacklabs at Hacklab Summit Finland 2015 in Tampere we had to make the move. After that we have found a place for our hacklab, renovated it to suit our purposes and after that had fun participating and arranging many wonderful events. </p>

<p>It was time for cake!</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/cake.jpg" alt="alt"></p>

<p>We would like to thank all those wonderful people, companies and institutions who have supported us during our first year!</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Mikkeli Maker Day</title>
	  <link>//mikkeli-maker-day</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-02-13T10:45:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//mikkeli-maker-day</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>We were invited to plan and execute a small event at local library. Something that involves different examples from our hacklab projects. Something that could make people from junior to senior happy. Something that we can handle with our resources. We would also need a nice name for the event... mmh... this was the most difficult part. Eventually someone screamed out something like Mikkeli Maker Day. Close enough.</p>

<p>The plan was simple: let&#39;s gather our things and carry them there. First on display was an arcade cabinet (12 mm mdf, Retropie, some used parts, some new parts):</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/mmd4.JPG" alt="alt"></p>

<p>Of course we had to bring our tweeting cactus, Teuvo (he is @TeuvoHacklabMLI):</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/mmd3.JPG" alt="alt"> </p>

<p>...and Seppo, the clever robot seen at HSF&#39;16:</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/mmd2.JPG" alt="alt"></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Seppo the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Robot?src=hash">#Robot</a> and unexpected obstacles appearing in his way... <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Mikkeli?src=hash">#Mikkeli</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Maker?src=hash">#Maker</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Day?src=hash">#Day</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/Mikkelikirjasto">@Mikkelikirjasto</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ERNOD?src=hash">#ERNOD</a> <a href="https://t.co/kyy6AUhNfU">pic.twitter.com/kyy6AUhNfU</a></p>&mdash; Hacklab Mikkeli (@HacklabMikkeli) <a href="https://twitter.com/HacklabMikkeli/status/698455624229715969">February 13, 2016</a></blockquote>

<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>More photos and some videos can be found at Hacklab Mikkeli&#39;s <a href="https://twitter.com/HacklabMikkeli">Twitter</a> and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/hacklabmikkeli/">Facebook</a> accounts.</p>

<p><i>The inviting party for the event was Mikkeli City Library working in co-operation with ERNOD project. They had a media club which themed in finding a use for discarded library books.</i></p>

<p><img src="/public/images/mmd5.JPG" alt="alt"></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>7-band equalizer</title>
	  <link>//seven-band-equalizer</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-02-05T15:41:41+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//seven-band-equalizer</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Not yet FFT, but getting close, this is simple 7-band graphic equalizer. Microphone amplifier, which has fixed gain of 20db, measures
surrounding noises. These noises are then fed to msgeq7-chip, made by MSI. Bit expensive chip, and so far only sparkfun seems to sell them.
What it does, is creates 7-band of different frequency regions, all are peak-detected and well filtered. Also, it creates 20db amplification.
This dc-voltage from msgeq7 is then fed to teensy 3.2, microcontroller that does rest of magic; controls msgeq7, reads and stores values, as well controls i2c 
bus OLED screen (128x64, blue colour). There is also bit conversion made before showing data, and that is just simple mapping function.
I don&#39;t have audio shield yet, but couple of those should arrive next week, and with that is possible to manipulate/mix and stuff like that real time at 16bit/44khz (cd quality)
as well as control real time FFT. But, even this simple version works well:</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oXUSYADG080" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Industrial Hackathon at Kuortti</title>
	  <link>//industrial-hackathon-at-kuortti</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-01-01T20:09:41+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//industrial-hackathon-at-kuortti</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Most likely the first hackathon of 2016 in region of Southern Savo began today 16:00 at Kuortti. This time it was <a href="http://www.industrialhackathon.fi/">Industrial Hackathon</a> with aim to improve processes of two local companies. These two hosting companies are <a href="http://www.pelaser.fi/">Pelaser</a> <a href="http://www.plastep.fi/">Plastep</a>. Pelaser works with processing steel plates and sheet metal parts. Plastep is a plastic production company.</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/kuortti-1.jpg" alt="alt"></p>

<p>Challenges for Pelaser are about logistics and pricing. Finding a solution or developing an application to improve the transparency and efficiency of internal logistics. The pricing challenge in detail is to find a solution or develop an application that intelligently automates the interal product pricing process.</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/kuortti-2.jpg" alt="alt"></p>

<p>Plastep challenges concentrate on common operational picture and quality. The challenges about common operational picture could be solved by developing an application that improvaes situational awareness of production status. Quality challenge aims to improve quality control and traceability throughout the whole manufacturing process. </p>

<p><img src="/public/images/kuortti-3.jpg" alt="alt"></p>

<p>It was also really nice to meet again people who participated our <a href="http://mikkeli.hacklab.fi/2015/04/13/space-apps-challenge-8-great-projects-as-a-result/">NASA Space Apps Hackathon</a> in April 2015. All of them had the same enthusiasm as before to solve the given challenges. About 18 hours time left for hacking...</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Testing AtTiny85's</title>
	  <link>//Testing%20AtTiny85's</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-01-01T20:09:41+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//Testing%20AtTiny85's</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><em>Testing....</em>
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/sW9Hx79.jpg" alt="AtTiny85_test">
Some projects doesn&#39;t need big&#39;n beefy microcontroller, this little one can tackle many projects like RTC clock
or say matrises &amp; cubes with shift registers.  Clock frequency is selectable between 1Mhz-20Mhz, but 16 seems to be enough. 16 needs external crystal,
but some people have managed to install it as internal freguency.
Only problem with this chip is that there is no hardware serial (well, there is i2c bus but needs to be enabled separately, bit different than normal serial), but that can be created with code. Test code I burned was just simple
10hz led-blinker, but that&#39;s enough proof whether ic works at all, and It&#39;s fast to load this code.</p>

<p>After testing, better to store these accordingly, ready to be used now:
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/i5yK14Q.jpg" alt="AtTiny85__test_OK"> </p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Elektroniikkalabran varustelu</title>
	  <link>//elektroniikkalabran-varustelu</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-11-19T19:30:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//elektroniikkalabran-varustelu</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Hacklab Mikkelin ensimmäinen toimintavuosi alkaa lähestyä loppuaan. Vuoteen mahtui niin perustaminen helmikuussa kuin Fuugin säätiön rahoituksen saaminen myöhemmin keväällä. Käytännössä rahoituksen avulla oli mahdollista saada toimintaan nopea lähtö ja toteuttaa missiota alusta saakka.</p>

<p><a href="http://fuug.fi/saatio/">Fuugin säätiö</a> rahoitti Hacklab Mikkelin työtilan varustelua yhteensä 2000 eurolla. Avustuksella rahoitettiin mm. 3D-tulostin, joka tilattiin osina ja koottiin itse. Kokoaminen oli opettavainen projekti jo itsessään. Tulostin on myös yksi varustelun vetonauloista sekä tapahtumissa että työtilassa. Avustuksen turvin hankittiin uteliaiden käyttöön myös tulostuslankaa.</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/fuug-1.jpg" alt=""></p>

<p>3D-tulostin ja asiaankuuluva pikakorjaus teipillä.</p>

<p>Lisäksi rahoituksella varustettiin uskottava elektroniikkapaja, johon kuuluu kolme työpistettä, juotosasemia, juotostelineitä, yleismittareita, teholähteitä, oskilloskooppi, logiikka-analysaattori, Arduinoja, Raspberry Pi 2 -tietokoneita ja tietysti paljon yhteiskäyttöön tarkoitettuja peruskomponentteja ja työkaluja. Elektroniikkapaja on ahkerassa käytössä viikoittain ja siellä on työstetty monia projekteja kuten moottoroitua longboardia, omavalmisteista syntetisaattoria, IoT-leivänpaahdinta ja erilaisia robotteja, sensoreita ja tietenkin vilkkuvaloja.</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/fuug-2.jpg" alt=""></p>

<p>Elektroniikkapaja alkaa muistuttaa ulkonäöltään perinteistä Hacklabia. Kuvassa myös MadBot: pölynimurin ja Twitter-botin risteytys.</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/fuug-3.jpg" alt=""></p>

<p>Pajassa tuunattu tee-se-itse syntetisaattori ja Fuugin rahoituksella ostettu digitaalinen oskilloskooppi.</p>

<p>Varustelun ansiosta Hacklab on voinut tarjota jäsenilleen ja muille uteliaille avoimen työtilan sekä järjestää useita tapahtumia mm. kansainvälisellä EU koodiviikolla tapahtuneen Internet of Things -hackathonin. Hacklab tarjoaa myös ilmaisia ja avoimia elektroniikan ja 3D-tulostamisen peruskursseja. Työtila koostuu elektroniikkapajasta, 3D-tulostus- ja tietokonetilasta, sotkuisen työn tilasta ja hengailuloungesta.</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/fuug-4.jpg" alt=""></p>

<p>Internet of Things hackathon, osana kansainvälistä EU Koodiviikkoa. Kuvassa edustettuina Open Knowledge Finland, API:Suomi sekä kolmen eri Hacklabin perustajia. Kiitos avustuksen turvin ostettujen varusteiden, tämäkin tapahtuma oli mahdollista toteuttaa.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>4x4x4 led cube</title>
	  <link>//4x4x4-led-cube</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-11-17T12:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//4x4x4-led-cube</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Enought complex project in both as mechanical and, possibly, how complex pattern one wants to show up on cube.
As this is 4-square cube, pattern can&#39;t be much complicated, so i added bit more touch in with clock and . 
Time is in memory of special chip. If you have normal radio-clock, you might have noticed that when/if main power goes out
so does time, gets nulled and must be set again. RTC chip keeps time, and is handy also when making stuff to happen in excact 
intervals like putting coffee machine or car heater on, you name it.
The idea behind using mirror-plating is to create same illusion as in infinity mirrors seen on web:
When general room is brightly lit, mirror-plating acts like mirror. When it&#39;s dark, you can see throught it
This is how it looks in bright room:
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/tnVL1M5.jpg" alt="Brightroomcube-off">
Bright room, with power:
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/z8CHEUc.jpg" alt="Brightroomcube-on">
Dark room, power on:
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/hHg1sDC.jpg" alt="darkroomcube-on"></p>

<p><em>Cube construction</em>
Construction of even small cubes can be tricky process, but small things matter,
like supporting and holding things together while swinging around with soledring iron.
That said, it&#39;s important that joints are smooth, and used small amount of solder, you don&#39;t want any shortcircuits in finished product!
Construction starts by checking(DOA&#39;s and other malfunctions can be possible)  and bending cathodes of each led.
On the background is seen handy jig, just plywood, with holes drilled, in how frequent one wants cube to be.
The thinner it is, the harder it is to solder and transparency suffers
the thicker, easier to solder, but takes more space and must be looked farther away
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/8NEjrJM.jpg" alt="ledbent">
Then, bent leds are placed in series in a way, clusters of 3, which are then soldered cathoded together.
Alligator clip holds led together while soldering
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/pYIeVzH.jpg" alt="ledrow">
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/6dALH0K.jpg" alt="ledcluster">
The end cathode of each led rows, is slighly bent to make it easier to join them together at last row
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/6xjpThL.jpg" alt="ledclusterbentcathode">
rows circuit
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/BWwmAhU.jpg" alt="circuitrow">
The bend soldered on last row, forgot to say, last row has 4 leds in row, so there&#39;s 3 pieces of 3 leds rows, and one 4 led rows, on each layer (4 layers)
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/KJzzVjD.jpg" alt="bentsoldered">
Sadly, i didn&#39;t take photo of situation where leds are floating, but there is situation when leds are &#39;&#39;floating&#39;&#39; unsupported on other end
Small piece of wire is joined to &#39;&#39;floating&#39;&#39; end of layer
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/8t7L5ZJ.jpg" alt="layersupport">
small hook, easier to solder and start soldering that prementioned support
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/FuveFoc.jpg" alt="layersupporthook">
layers circuit
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/i561j4k.jpg" alt="circuitlayer">
finished layer, DON&#39;T cut that tail of cathode yet, it serves as testing post for each layers cathode (in this scale of project, it&#39;s better to test now and then)
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/58gWZHZ.jpg" alt="finishedlayer">
with added strength for faith
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/0o1ac7F.jpg" alt="finishedlayershrinks">
Now comes annoying part: you have 4 layers, gotta solder them together top of each other.
Bend each anode of each led, this serves as base where to plant next layer coming.
When you start soldering, solder each bar/columns anodes togehter, so in end product you have only 4 cathodes, but anodes 16.
Hard to describe...this is one of annoying parts of this project!
finished cube should look like this.
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/0tPz59O.jpg" alt="finishedcube">
Then it&#39;s placed on veroboard, painted black on purpose. Also, now there are layer cathodes going down too, they decide what layer is on at what time.
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/AqHo7mZ.jpg" alt="finishedcubeblackpcb">
And you need to make connection for all anodes and layer cathodes, make some sort of order/organization to make it clear for yourself.
Green wires are layer cathodes
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/rLw0rSR.jpg" alt="finishedcubebackpcb"></p>

<p>*Controller board (shift regsisters and RTC)
In control, shift registers play big role: what they do, simply put, control in this case lot of input/outputs in few microcontroller pins
without these, 20 pins would be needed, but now 3 is needed
Data is sent in serial-format, these shift registers i use are 74595 Serial in-paraller out and they are very fast, no idea how many you can chain together
RTC is not yet seen in this photo
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/jxyfEqz.jpg" alt="controllerfront">
had to place jumper wires behind board too
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/U6eQ1Ze.jpg" alt="controllerback">
RTC is shown here, in breadboard, i2c-bus, ds1307
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/IPYgFDx.jpg" alt="RTC">
to further eliminate pins needed in microcontroller, i used i2c in lcd too, it goes in same pins with RTC
The i2c enables just this, placing many stuff in same pins. Think it like addresses: each house has their own address, and get their own mail
Didn&#39;t have any OLED screens, but lcd will do.
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/5EtCwfC.jpg" alt="i2clcd">
As microcontroller i use arduino pro mini, due small size mainly, FTDI-USB converter also seen on photo
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/VdtENUV.jpg" alt="micro">
And here&#39;s all electronic stuff that must be stuffed in enclosure, excepct FTDI, that is only used in programming, or as as USB power adapter if you want
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/amdLySk.jpg" alt="electronics"></p>

<p><em>Enclosure</em>
This part is much easier if you decide to buy plastic box, or steel you know the drill
But, i decided to make one from oak
There is used stopped grooves, so special technique is used, wooden blocks are used as stops do deside lenght of groove
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/Mdkixhw.jpg" alt="groovebit">
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/Jq94y29.jpg" alt="groovestops">
Also, groove, or more like straight plunge bit is used in making hole for lcd
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/mGLJpEf.jpg" alt="lcdhole">
Box thus far, without finishing
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/HRsAzKE.jpg" alt="boxunfinished">
Raw cuts for frames
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/mnQaCHa.jpg" alt="frames">
Now there&#39;s linseed oil on box, along with mounted electronic stuff inside
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/7Q7qH4Z.jpg" alt="finishedbox">
On back there is power and programming connections
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/dJHRHzN.jpg" alt="finishedboxback">
I didn&#39;t feel confortable cutting glass, so i decided to try plexiglass for windows: cut grooves and slam/snap along table edge
I highly suggest using safety glasses, plexi can be unpredictable
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/0FOvFfc.jpg" alt="cuttingplexi">
And couple of shots from different situations, mainly to show how mirror plating behaves
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/65wPjIQ.jpg" alt="brightoff">
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/kMNv5ny.jpg" alt="brighton">
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/Vrygzwn.jpg" alt="darkon"></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>CodeWeek EU and IoT Hackathon</title>
	  <link>//codeweek-eu</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-10-12T17:25:41+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//codeweek-eu</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>To celebrate <a href="http://www.codeweek.eu/">the Europe Code Week 2015</a> Hacklab Mikkeli organized its own event in Mikkeli. Our event was built from bunch of different sub-events. The major event was Internet of Things Hackathon which describes itself with its name. Other events included planning and luckily also starting local <a href="http://koodikerho.fi/">Koodikerho</a> activity, 3D modelling and printing workshop, <a href="http://www.apisuomi.fi/">API:Suomi</a> meeting which lead to starting API Meetup community to Mikkeli, and last but not least <a href="http://openfinlandchallenge.fi/">Open Finland Challenge</a> workshop.</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/hackathon-liste.jpg" alt="Hacklab Mikkeli member liste teaching some basics of electronics"></p>

<p>One quite interesting project was presented by locusf (Aleksi Suomalainen) from <a href="http://kuopio.hacklab.fi/">Kuopio Hacklab</a>. He has been working on a project that combines Raspberry Pi with SailfishOS. A SailPi tablet. For more detailed information see his blog article: <a href="https://sailpi.wordpress.com/2015/10/11/deployment-and-use-of-the-sailpi-tablet-as-real-standalone-tablet/">Deployment and use of the SailPi tablet as real standalone tablet</a></p>

<p><img src="/public/images/hackathon-boots.jpg" alt=""></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Digital City Adventure 2015</title>
	  <link>//digital-city-adventure-2015</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-10-04T14:25:41+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//digital-city-adventure-2015</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Hacklab Mikkeli had a possibility to host a checkpoint in Digital City Adventure 2015. Of course we accepted the challenge and did our best making the checkpoint a nice experience for all participants.</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/dks-1.jpg" alt=""></p>

<p>Digital City Adventure is a 24-hour event where the whole city of Mikkeli turns into a digital playfield. Participants explore the city and solve puzzles at the checkpoints using their own mobile devices. For more information see <a href="http://www.digitaalinenkaupunkiseikkailu.fi/info/en/">Digital City Adventure site</a>.</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/dks-2.jpg" alt=""></p>

<p>We opened our checkpoint same the game began. Within first ten minutes participants started arriving. First it looked like we can handle the situation easily. We could even count the visitors. We could instruct the visitors making a protective gear against harmful radiation. </p>

<p>After first hour things changed. The hacklab was totally crowded. All 90 meters of tin foil was used. No more protection. In total we counted 210 visitors. Real figure is something like &plusmn;50. In any case lots of nice people, lots of them interested in hacklab activity. We hope to see them again on open Thursdays!</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/dks-3.jpg" alt=""></p>

<p>Part of our checkpoint was this weird gizmo. Something the Digital City Adventure participants had to solve to get full points from our checkpoint. First they had to access our local network by using social engineering. </p>

<p>Next they had to access web server - once again by using social engineering for clues - to control lights. In certain combination the lights made it possible to hear the correct code for the checkpoint. In Morse code.</p>

<p><em>Hacklab Mikkeli&#39;s late summer has been busy. We have been building programmable robots with 7th graders (see <a href="http://yle.fi/uutiset/robotiikka_tulee_peruskouluihin_kylla_tama_aina_ruotsintunnit_voittaa/8299602">YLE News</a> for details). We also spent one whole day at Mikkeli University of Applied Sciences on a Hobby Fair recruiting new members.</em></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
