<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>mikkeli.hacklab.fi</title>
   
   <link>http://mikkeli.hacklab.fi</link>
   <description>Avoin ja yhteisöllinen työtila tieteestä, teknologiasta ja digitaalisesta taiteesta kiinnostuneille Mikkelissä &bull; An open and community-based workspace for people with interest in science, technology and digital arts in Mikkeli</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> Hacklab Mikkeli</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Mittaustekniikan oppitunnit alkavat</title>
	  <link>//mittaustekniikka_2016</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-04-07T12:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//mittaustekniikka_2016</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Mittaustekniikan oppitunnit alkavat. Opimme käyttämään mm. oskilloskooppia, spektrianalysaattoria ja vektoripiirianalysaattoria.</p>

<p>Ensimmäinen tunti on lauantaina <em>9.4.</em> kello <em>10-13:30</em>.</p>

<p>Toinen tunti on sunnuntaina <em>17.4.</em> kello <em>18-21</em>.</p>

<p>Myöhempien tuntien aikataulu julkaistaan myöhemmin.</p>

<p>Tulkaa vapaasti osallistumaan!
Oppimateriaali löytyy <a href="https://www.gitbook.com/%E2%80%A6/hacklabm%E2%80%A6/mittaustekniikka/details">GitBookista</a></p>

<p>Esitietovaatimuksia ei ole, mutta sähköopin perusasioiden osaaminen helpottaa osallistumista. Huomatkaa, että mittaamisen hallitseminen vähentää huomattavasti turhautumista myöhemmillä elektroniikan kursseilla (mm. digitaalitekniikka ja mikrokontrollerit).</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>PCB-etching with vinegar.</title>
	  <link>//PCB-etching%20with%20vinegar</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-04-05T12:30:41+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//PCB-etching%20with%20vinegar</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Time to cook.</p>

<p>So, decided to give shot of making pcb&#39;s at home now that I found rather easy method. To make PCB&#39;s at home, methods are either etching or using special router.
When etching, mostly used stuff is ferrid chrolide, expensive but fast stuff. Then comes combination that involves muriatic acid (another nasty poison). This method that I used doesn&#39;t use that poisonous stuff at all
, only acetone is considered as poison here (so no safety gear reguired, only with acetone I&#39;d recommend using safety gear, it&#39;s 100% acetone we&#39;re dealing with, not nail polish remover)
To begin, we need laser printer (used to print mask/pcb tracks. No, you can&#39;t use inkjet because it just doesn&#39;t work.) The idea of using laser printer is that laser printer uses toner which is then transferred to pcb via either chemical transfer or heat transfer. Heat transfer is more common,
but has downside of possible deform of PCB due uneven heat betweeb surfaces.  Chemical transfer uses acetone to dilute toner that then is left behind to PCB.
also you need some fine sandpaper/steel wool to clean pcb.
All other stuff can be bought at hardware store, but hydrogen is bought at pharmacy. Don&#39;t combine acetone to hydrogen peroxide, I read it can be quite nasty, but I doubt is as this hydrogen peroxide is quite mild (you can pour it open wound and It&#39;s used as healing stuff)
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/k1HlVBO.jpg" alt="Incredients"></p>

<p>First thing is to print out pcb tracks, in mirrored image (use glossy, shiny paper, like photopaper). Then, acetone is placed on cleaned pcb and mask that we printed is placed face-down on that acetone pool. Now, DON&#39;T move
mask while it&#39;s setting/diluting. After few secods appply only perpendicular pressure evenly on all areas of mask. You should see mask throught paper, and this is good,
it means acetone has effected toner. Now, wait until you can&#39;t see toner anymore, paper is now dry from acetone. Next you place that pcb on water so we can peel that paper off safely. If all wen&#39;t well, all toner should be on pcb, but none on paper.
Wee, transfer is done!
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/LKlJG8B.jpg" alt="transferok"></p>

<p>Next is to make solution for etching, ratio that I use is 50/50 vinegar 10% and hydrogen peroxide 3%.Ventilated place is not mantadory, only thing that stinks is vinegar. Salt is added all the time during process.
When you add salt, action takes place and bubbling will start.  Do use proper salt, not just some potassium stuff, it must be natrium salt, good stuff.
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/1tK5c0W.jpg" alt="bath">
You should also clean all oxides that appear, as well as blue powder (copper acetate, that can also be re-used) 
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/b1142Gu.jpg" alt="dirt">
When job is done, mask is removed with acetone. If you decide to dispose this blue water, be aware it has copper acetate in it, so it is
hazard-waste, but you can evoparate liguid so only powder is left. Don&#39;t drink it....
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/0nIDtB1.jpg" alt="bluewater">
As you can see, mine product didn&#39;t came up 100%, and that&#39;s because there are stuff to consider like use of toner and proper cleaning of pcb as well as etching agent (portions of vinegar + hydrogen peroxide)
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/nGxT5MK.jpg?1" alt="finished"></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Spectrum analyzer and vector network analyzer</title>
	  <link>//spectrum-analyzer-and-vector-network-analyzer</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-03-29T12:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//spectrum-analyzer-and-vector-network-analyzer</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Hacklab Mikkeli has bought RF equipment: Rohde &amp; Schwarz FSB 100Hz &mdash;
5GHz spectrum analyzer, and HP 8711B vector network analyzer. They can be
used to measure, for example, frequency, amplitude, spectrum, S/N ratio, THD,
antenna SWR, amplitude response and phase response in a wide frequency range.
The spectrum analyzer can additionally be used as a radio tuner!
Both devices are available to subscribers, and require training to operate. </p>

<p><img src="/public/images/rf-equipment-closeup.jpg" alt="Closeup of equipment"></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Car voltage meter</title>
	  <link>//Car%20voltage%20meter</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-03-17T22:46:41+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//Car%20voltage%20meter</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Part of this bigger project, car computer, I wanted sepatate meter for voltage, in case of alternator fault.
Idea is simple; voltage divider circuit converts voltage for more suitable level for AtTiny85 that can handle up to 5 volts to ADC (analog to digital converter
and Attiny then converts this data and shows it in 7-segment display. Also there is bargraph display to give another perspective, easier to look on-road that charge level is in &quot;green&quot;
region, not too much or too low.
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/hHYGoGx.jpg" alt="voltagemetercircuit"></p>

<p>Once again, prototyping started at breadboard, and I also made AtTiny programming shield for easier coding sessions, no need to play that much with jumper wires.
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/QUHLYzB.jpg" alt="voltagemeterbreadboard">
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/RMdzoNE.jpg" alt="voltagemetershield"></p>

<p>There was quite chore to place all stuff in confined area (inline fuse is also coming in final installation):
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/oflhAzT.jpg" alt="voltagemeterproto">
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/vHHT4UJ.jpg" alt="voltagemeterproto1"></p>

<p>Another trouble was finding suitable enclosure, but recently bought 52mm dashboard meter casings, and all that was needed was meter panel, solution was 3d-printer.
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/AFH2g7X.jpg" alt="voltagemeter3dprint">
And in the end, it looks quite good in dark too:
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/kgAxl9h.jpg?1" alt="voltagemeterdark"></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Started doing car computer</title>
	  <link>//Starting%20of%20car%20computer</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-03-03T22:46:41+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//Starting%20of%20car%20computer</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Long time I&#39;ve longed for this project as I lacked skill. Now was great time for this project, as I&#39;ve stumbled on teensy 3.2. 
Teensy 3.2 has horsepower and memory for pretty much all projects possiblse, and in this case I&#39;m planning to combine quite many tasks
to one microcontroller; car computer data, RTC, gps tracking(which also has combined feature of theft-alarm, using SIM800L) as well as
real-time audio manipulation along FFT. First things first, I started checking simple commands, like read battery voltage, and true indeed,
it worked. The device I use for talking with car computer (ECU) is sparkfun&#39;s obd-uart board, which allows any serial capable device to serve as end-terminal
for diagnostics.
I&#39;ve so far managed to put code that allows pretty much all real-time data to be checked, even throttle and stress levels, as well as draw bar display of reguested values.
In this photo is initial test which has echo as well as carbage characters, but they were ok back the initial testing whether my car&#39;s protocol is supported or not.
Also, screen is in photo 20x4 alphanumeric LCD, but currently I&#39;m using 0,96&quot; 128x32 OLED, it has many benefits over lcd, except size, but I&#39;ll place it anyway right on front of my eyes so 0,96&quot; is enought.
<img src="http://i.imgur.com/taSULgy.jpg?1" alt="computer"></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Blender Course Report</title>
	  <link>//blender-course-report</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-02-20T12:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//blender-course-report</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>First course to begin our year 2016 was 3D modelling basics with <a href="http://www.blender.org/">Blender</a>. We asked what courses our community was interested in and 3D modelling basics was voted to first place. Luckily we have some talented Blender users in our members who also volunteered to lead the course. </p>

<p><img src="/public/images/blender-course.jpg" alt="Photo: People at Blender course"> </p>

<p>Earlier our courses have been about eletronics and robotics, so now we needed a whole different layout of tables and seating. Course material and instructing was also designed to suit the skills of participating people which varied from beginner to advanced. These facts made the course a test in many ways.</p>

<p>Everything went fine. Even better than expected. Many of participants found 3D modelling interesting and want to learn more. Easily worth the early wakeup on Saturday morning.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Hacklab Mikkeli 1 Year!</title>
	  <link>//hacklab-mikkeli-1-year</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-02-19T22:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//hacklab-mikkeli-1-year</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>We have survived as a registered association for one whole year! One year ago we met and decided to make this thing official - 19 brave hackers signed our charter of foundation. Of course we had began planning the hacklab earlier but after receiving huge support from other Finnish hacklabs at Hacklab Summit Finland 2015 in Tampere we had to make the move. After that we have found a place for our hacklab, renovated it to suit our purposes and after that had fun participating and arranging many wonderful events. </p>

<p>It was time for cake!</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/cake.jpg" alt="alt"></p>

<p>We would like to thank all those wonderful people, companies and institutions who have supported us during our first year!</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Mikkeli Maker Day</title>
	  <link>//mikkeli-maker-day</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-02-13T10:45:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//mikkeli-maker-day</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>We were invited to plan and execute a small event at local library. Something that involves different examples from our hacklab projects. Something that could make people from junior to senior happy. Something that we can handle with our resources. We would also need a nice name for the event... mmh... this was the most difficult part. Eventually someone screamed out something like Mikkeli Maker Day. Close enough.</p>

<p>The plan was simple: let&#39;s gather our things and carry them there. First on display was an arcade cabinet (12 mm mdf, Retropie, some used parts, some new parts):</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/mmd4.JPG" alt="alt"></p>

<p>Of course we had to bring our tweeting cactus, Teuvo (he is @TeuvoHacklabMLI):</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/mmd3.JPG" alt="alt"> </p>

<p>...and Seppo, the clever robot seen at HSF&#39;16:</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/mmd2.JPG" alt="alt"></p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Seppo the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Robot?src=hash">#Robot</a> and unexpected obstacles appearing in his way... <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Mikkeli?src=hash">#Mikkeli</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Maker?src=hash">#Maker</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Day?src=hash">#Day</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/Mikkelikirjasto">@Mikkelikirjasto</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ERNOD?src=hash">#ERNOD</a> <a href="https://t.co/kyy6AUhNfU">pic.twitter.com/kyy6AUhNfU</a></p>&mdash; Hacklab Mikkeli (@HacklabMikkeli) <a href="https://twitter.com/HacklabMikkeli/status/698455624229715969">February 13, 2016</a></blockquote>

<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>More photos and some videos can be found at Hacklab Mikkeli&#39;s <a href="https://twitter.com/HacklabMikkeli">Twitter</a> and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/hacklabmikkeli/">Facebook</a> accounts.</p>

<p><i>The inviting party for the event was Mikkeli City Library working in co-operation with ERNOD project. They had a media club which themed in finding a use for discarded library books.</i></p>

<p><img src="/public/images/mmd5.JPG" alt="alt"></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>7-band equalizer</title>
	  <link>//seven-band-equalizer</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-02-05T15:41:41+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//seven-band-equalizer</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Not yet FFT, but getting close, this is simple 7-band graphic equalizer. Microphone amplifier, which has fixed gain of 20db, measures
surrounding noises. These noises are then fed to msgeq7-chip, made by MSI. Bit expensive chip, and so far only sparkfun seems to sell them.
What it does, is creates 7-band of different frequency regions, all are peak-detected and well filtered. Also, it creates 20db amplification.
This dc-voltage from msgeq7 is then fed to teensy 3.2, microcontroller that does rest of magic; controls msgeq7, reads and stores values, as well controls i2c 
bus OLED screen (128x64, blue colour). There is also bit conversion made before showing data, and that is just simple mapping function.
I don&#39;t have audio shield yet, but couple of those should arrive next week, and with that is possible to manipulate/mix and stuff like that real time at 16bit/44khz (cd quality)
as well as control real time FFT. But, even this simple version works well:</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oXUSYADG080" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Industrial Hackathon at Kuortti</title>
	  <link>//industrial-hackathon-at-kuortti</link>
	  <author>Hacklab Mikkeli</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-01-01T20:09:41+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//industrial-hackathon-at-kuortti</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Most likely the first hackathon of 2016 in region of Southern Savo began today 16:00 at Kuortti. This time it was <a href="http://www.industrialhackathon.fi/">Industrial Hackathon</a> with aim to improve processes of two local companies. These two hosting companies are <a href="http://www.pelaser.fi/">Pelaser</a> <a href="http://www.plastep.fi/">Plastep</a>. Pelaser works with processing steel plates and sheet metal parts. Plastep is a plastic production company.</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/kuortti-1.jpg" alt="alt"></p>

<p>Challenges for Pelaser are about logistics and pricing. Finding a solution or developing an application to improve the transparency and efficiency of internal logistics. The pricing challenge in detail is to find a solution or develop an application that intelligently automates the interal product pricing process.</p>

<p><img src="/public/images/kuortti-2.jpg" alt="alt"></p>

<p>Plastep challenges concentrate on common operational picture and quality. The challenges about common operational picture could be solved by developing an application that improvaes situational awareness of production status. Quality challenge aims to improve quality control and traceability throughout the whole manufacturing process. </p>

<p><img src="/public/images/kuortti-3.jpg" alt="alt"></p>

<p>It was also really nice to meet again people who participated our <a href="http://mikkeli.hacklab.fi/2015/04/13/space-apps-challenge-8-great-projects-as-a-result/">NASA Space Apps Hackathon</a> in April 2015. All of them had the same enthusiasm as before to solve the given challenges. About 18 hours time left for hacking...</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
